

# Md Mehedi Hasan

Address | Palton ,Dhaka-1000,Bangladesh

Phone I +8801918505569

mehedihasan60.mh35@gmail.com **Email** 

Portfolio I https://mehediswe.me/



**LinkedIn I** <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahadi-hasan-576371151/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahadi-hasan-576371151/</a>

# **CAREER SUMMARY**

I have strong faith in hard working, interpersonal skills to achieve the set target or goals in a team environment, integrity and always want to improve myself to become well skilled. I believe positive thinking and hardworking is the key to success.

Gender:- Male | Date Of Birth:- 06-05-1997 | Nationality:- Bangladeshi

- 3+ Years of experience with 6+ years of programming skills
- Development experience in Desktop Apps, Web Apps, Mobile Apps, API
- Built various applications with React Js, Vue Js, React Native, Electron Js, Node JS, Next Js.
- -Analytical skill to understand documentation

# **EXPERIENCE**

February 2020 - Now

## Software Engineer | Full Time

Company | Rise Up Labs

Ersadul Hoque(CEO), Uttara, Dhaka (Website:-https://riseuplabs.com)

ISO certified | Information Technology

#### Responsibilities:

- Development & Maintaining Projects for UNICEF, FAO of UN, GOV
- Web Front-End Development, Android/IOS Development
- Follows the software development lifecycle.
- Create and maintain software documentation
- Maintaining and improving existing codebases and peer review code changes.

#### Software Developer | Full Time

March 2019 - january 2019

Company | ASB ICT Limited

Mostafizur Rahman(Director), Panthapath, Dhaka, (Website:- http://asbict.com)

**Business Sector** | IT consulting and software development company **Responsibilities:** 

- Development & Maintaining Projects for Government school, college website
- Integrate data from various back-end services and databases

# **PROJECTS**

### Safer Internet for Children, UNICEF

Web based gaming Application / Vue is

https://safeinternet.unicefbangladesh.org/

#### NCB e-Learning Course for Bangladesh, GOV, FAO

Website, Desktop and Mac App / Vue is ,Electron is

https://ncbelearning.fpmu.gov.bd/

Similar type other project ,Client UNICEF with mobile app

https://adolescent.nnsop.org/

# Information & Management System, UNICEF

Web based gaming Application / Vue js

- https://volunteer.unicefbangladesh.org/
- <a href="https://riseuplabs.com/volunteer-information-hub/">https://riseuplabs.com/volunteer-information-hub/</a>

### **U-Report App, UNICEF**

Android Application / Vue js , java, PHP

 https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.riseuplabs.ureport. general&hl=en\_US&gl=US

4th place on Daffodil International University(Team: Tensor), DIU Take-OFF Programming Contest 2018

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### **Volunteered Organizations- (BDBO)**

 Protiddhoni Foundation, sector commanders forum-Liberation war'71, Bangladesh Biology Olympiad (BDBO)

# **Daffodil International University /Bsc in Software Engineering**

April 2015 - April 2019

CGPA-3.12 Out of 4.00.

#### **EDUCATION**

Lions School and College, Rangpur / Higher Secondary Certificate

2012 - 2014

CGPA-4.40 Out of 5.00.

# Bhadauria School and College, Dinajpur / Secondary School Certificate

2010 - 2012

CGPA-4.56 Out of 5.00.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS & TOOLS

**Development**: TypeScript, React JS,Vue js, ,React Native,Electron Js,,Next Js,Node JS,Create.js,PhaserJS,Three.js,Matter.js,HTML5, CSS3, REST API, MongoDB, MySQL.

Deployment Tools: AWS, Babel, Webpack, CI/CD, Git, GitHub

Programming Languages: JavaScript, PHP, OOP, C

Design: UX, UI, MVP, Requirements analysis, Persona & Scenario

**Prototyping**: Photoshop, Sketch, Adobe XD.

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### **Problem Solving**

https://www.coderbyte.com/profile/saiful24/

## **Projects**

https://github.com/Mahadi74/

# **University Projects**

https://github.com/Mahadi74/Socail-Education-site

#### REFERENCE

#### Md. Habibur Rahman

Lecturer Department of Software Engineering E-mail: habibur.swe@diu.edu.bd Cell-Phone: +8801770948923

#### Mr. Md. Anwar Hossen

Senior Lecturer Department of Software Engineering

E-mail: anwar.swe@diu.edu.bd Cell-Phone: +8801717976009, +8801516105789

I, the undersigned, hereby assure that, according to my knowledge and belief, this CV correctly describes my qualification. So please give me an opportunity to have an interview to prove myself.

Respectfully yours, Md Mehedi Hasan

LAST MODIFIED: 11 / 06 / 2021